게임을 하려면
상대가 있어야지
Two can play at that game, soldier.
That's nice shooting, soldier!
잘 했네!
Mandrake, come here.
맨드레이크, 이리 오게
You calling me, Jack?
부르셨습니까?
이리 와서 좀 도와주게
Come over here
and help me with this belt.
I haven't had very much experience...
전 이런 기계엔
...with those sort of machines.
문외한이라서요
I've only ever pressed a button
in my old Spitfire.
전투기에서
단추만 눌러봤습니다
영국 여왕과 국가의
명예를 걸고 잡고 있어
In the name of Her Majesty and the
Continental Congress, feed me this belt.
저도 가서 돕고 싶지만
Jack, I'd love to come,
but what's happened, you see...
...the string in my leg is gone.
다리에 힘줄이 없습니다
- The what?
- The string. I never told you.
- 뭐라고?
- 모르고 계셨군요
I've got a gammy leg.
Oh, dear. Gone. Shot off.
다리를 총에 맞아
다친 적이 있죠
어서 오게
놈들이 오고 있어
Mandrake, come over here.
The redcoats are coming.
폭파되면 치명적
방사능 낙진이 생기고
When it is detonated, it will produce
enough radioactive fallout...
...so that in ten months...
10달이면
...the surface of the Earth
will be as dead as the moon!
지표는 달과 같이
황폐하게 된다고요!
Come on, De Sadesky!
That's ridiculous!
말도 안 되는 소리!
Our studies show even the worst fallout
is down to a safe level after two weeks.
아무리 심한 낙진도 2주 후면
안전단계에 이른다고 들었소
- You never heard of cobalt thorium G.
- What about it?
- 코발트 토륨 G를 모르는군
- 그게 뭐요?
Cobalt thorium G has
a radioactive half-life of 93 years.
방사성 원소 반감기가
93년에 이르는데
If you take 50 H bombs
in the 100 megaton range...
100메카톤수의
50개 폭탄에
코발트 토륨 G로
커버를 씌운 것으로
...and jacket them
with cobalt thorium G...
...when they are exploded,
they will produce a doomsday shroud...
폭발하게 되면 심판의 날에나
있을 법한 장막인
...a lethal cloud of radioactivity...
방사선 구름이 형성돼
지구를 93년은
휘감게 될 거요!
...which will encircle the Earth
for 93 years!
What a load of Commie bull.
I mean, after all.
빨갱이들 허풍은
알아줘야 한다니까
I'm afraid I don't understand
something, Alexi.
이해 안 되는 게 있소
Is the premier threatening to explode it
if our planes carry out their attack?
소련에선 우리측이 공격하면
그걸 터뜨리겠다는 겁니까?
No, sir. It is not a thing
a sane man would do.
정신이 제대로 박힌 인간은
못할 짓이죠
The doomsday machine is designed
to trigger itself automatically.
인류파멸의 흉기는
자동으로 작동됩니다
Surely you can disarm it somehow.
어쨌든
해제할 방법은 있겠죠?
인위적 저지 시엔
자동 폭파 됩니다
It is designed to explode if
any attempt is made to un-trigger it.
Automatically?
자동 폭파?
It's a Commie trick!
We're wasting valuable time!
빨갱이들 음모에
시간 낭비하고 있어요
Look at the big board!
They're getting ready to clobber us!
배치도를 보세요
우릴 쳐부술 태세라고요
미친 짓이군
왜 그런 걸 만들었소?
This is absolute madness.
Why should you build such a thing?
There are those of us
who fought against it.
반대의 무리도
있었습니다만
But in the end, we could not keep up
with the expense involved...
결국 무기확장 경쟁
우주개발 경쟁 등의
...in the arms race, the space race
and the peace race.
비용을 조달하기 힘들었죠
At the same time, our people grumbled
for more nylons and washing machines.
게다가 인민들은 생활고로
불평이 많았죠
Our doomsday scheme cost us
just a small fraction...
심판의 날 무기계획이
연간 국방비에서
차지하는 비율은
아주 미비합니다
...of what we have been spending on defense
in a single year.
The deciding factor was when we learned
your country was working similarly...
하지만 가장 큰 계기가 된 것은
미국 측에서도
비슷한 걸 만든다는
소문이었죠
...and we were afraid of a doomsday gap!
터무니 없는 소리
난 승인한 적 없소
This is preposterous! I've never
approved of anything like that.
뉴욕 타임즈에서 봤는데요
Our source was The New York Times.
Dr. Strangelove, do we have anything
like that in the works?
스트레인지러브 박사
그런 걸 만들고 있소?
잠시만요, 각하
A moment, please, Mr. President.
Under the authority granted me...
제 권한, 즉...
무기연구개발 국장으로서
...as director of weapons research
and development...
작년에
그와 같은 연구를
...I commissioned last year
a study of this project...
...by the Bland Corporation.
블랜드사에
의뢰했습니다
보고서를 살펴보니
Based on the findings of the report...
사실 핵무기와는
좀 달는데
...my conclusion was that this idea
was not a practical deterrent...
이 순간 모든 게
분명해지는군요
...for reasons which at this moment
must be all too obvious.
You mean it is possible for them
to have built such a thing?
저들이 그런 물건을 만들
가능성이 있다는 거요?
최소한의 원자력만 있어도
Mr. President, the technology required
is easily within the means...
...of even the smallest nuclear power.
가능한 기술입니다
만들려는 의지의 문제죠
It requires only the will to do so.
But how is it possible for this thing
to be triggered automatically...
자동으로 작동하면서
또 한편으론
...and at the same time
impossible to un-trigger?
저지가 불가능하다는 게
가능한 일이오?
가능의 문제가 아니라
Mr. President,
it is not only possible...
필수적인 요소입니다
...it is essential.
That is the whole idea
of this machine, you know.
바로 그 점이
기계의 특성입니다
Deterrence is the art of producing
in the mind of the enemy...
전쟁 억제력이란 적이
침공을 주저하게 만드는
기술입니다
...the fear of attack.
따라서 저지 불가능한
자동 기능은
And so because of the automated and
irrevocable decision-making process...
인류 파멸 무기를
...which rules out human meddling...
...the doomsday machine is terrifying...
주무르는 인간에게는...
두렵고 명확하여
...and simple to understand...
전쟁 억제 기능을
톡톡히 합니다
...and completely credible
and convincing.
I wish we had one of them
doomsday machines.
우리도 한 대 있었으면
좋겠군
But this is fantastic, Strangelove.
How can it be triggered automatically?
엄청난 기계야
어떻게 자동으로 작동하지?
It's remarkably simple to do that.
아주 간단한 원리죠
When you merely wish to bury bombs...
우선 폭탄을 매장하죠
...there's no limit to the size.
크기는 상관 없어요
After that, they are connected...
그리고 그것들을
거대한 컴퓨터들에
연결합니다
...to a gigantic complex of computers.
Now then, a specific and clearly
defined set of circumstances...
그리곤 폭탄이 폭발될
상황을 구체적이고
...under which the bombs
are to be exploded...
명확하게 설정해서
...is programmed into a tape memory bank.
컴퓨터에
프로그램화 하는 거죠
스트레인지러브?
Hmm. Strangelove?
What kind of a name is that?
That ain't no Kraut name, is it?
이름 한번 괴상하군
독일식 이름은 아닌데?
He changed it when he became a citizen.
시민권을 따면서
이름을 바꿨대
It used to be Merkwurdichliebe.
원래는 멕윅드리브였대
Well, a Kraut by any other name,
uh, Stainsey?
아무리 그래도
독일 놈이지?
The whole point of
the doomsday machine...
심판의 기계의 존재는
...is lost if you keep it a secret!
비밀로 하는 한
무용지물이죠
Why didn't you tell the world?
왜 비밀로 한 겁니까?
It was to be announced
at the Party Congress on Monday.
월요일에 인민회의에서
발표할 예정이었소
As you know,
the premier loves surprises.
서기장은 깜짝쇼를
좋아하시죠
평화는 우리 손으로
Stay with me, Mandrake.
조금만 더 견디게
총알을 더 줘
All right, now feed me.
Feed me, boy.
좀 더 안전한 쪽으로
옮기는 게 낫지 않을까요?
Don't you think we'd be better off
away from this flying glass?
We're okay here.
여기도 괜찮네
물에만 불소를
첨가했을 뿐 아니라
Mandrake, do you realize that
in addition to fluoridating the water...
...there are studies underway
to fluoridate salt, flour...
소금, 밀가루, 과일주스
비누, 설탕, 우유...
아이스크림에도
첨가한다는 얘기가 있네
...fruit juices, soup, sugar,
milk, ice cream?
Ice cream.
아이스크림!
- Children's ice cream.
- Good Lord.
- 애들이 먹는 아이스크림까지!
- 세상에
불소가 언제 처음
첨가된 줄 아나?
You know when fluoridation
first began?
모릅니다
No, I don't, Jack.
1946년이네
1946.
1946년이야!
1946, Mandrake.
전후 공산주의 음모이론과
동시에 일어났네
How does that coincide with
your postwar Commie conspiracy, huh?
너무나 뻔하지 않나?
It's incredibly obvious, isn't it?
A foreign substance is introduced
into our precious bodily fluids...
우리의 고귀한 체액에
외국 물질이 들어오고 있어
아무도 모르는 새 말야
...without the knowledge
of the individual.
선택의 여지도 없지
Certainly without any choice.
빨갱이의
본격적인 활동이야
That's the way a hard-core Commie works.
저기, 장군님
Jack. Tell me, Jack.
When did you first become--
언제 처음 그런 이론을
믿게 되셨죠?
Well, develop this theory?
Well, l--
글쎄...
처음 깨닫게 된 건
I first became aware of it, Mandrake...
육체적 사랑을
나눌 때였지
...during the physical act of love.
Yes, a profound sense of fatigue...
극도의 피로감...
공허감이 뒤따랐지
...feeling of emptiness followed.
Luckily I was able to interpret
these feelings correctly.
다행히 그 감정을
정확히 해석할 수 있었네
Loss of essence.
본질의 상실이지
I can assure you it has not recurred,
Mandrake.
그 후론
경험하기 힘들었네
Women sense my power...
여자들은
내 힘을 감지하고
...and they seek the life essence.
생명의 본질을 찾지
여자를 멀리하진 않지만
I do not avoid women, Mandrake.
But I do deny them my essence.
내 본질까지 내줄 순 없지
Yes, yes, Jack.
그렇겠죠
Cease fire!
사격 중지!
부하들이 항복했나 보군
My boys must have surrendered.
There it is.
그런가 보네요
Jack, listen.
장군님
아직 시간은 있으니
명령을 취소하는 게...
While there's still time, I beg you,
let's recall the Wing and--
자식과도 같던 부하들이...
Those boys were like my children.
날 실망시키는군
Now they let me down.
아닙니다
No, not a bit.
I'm sure they all gave it
their very best.
모두들 최선을 다했을 겁니다
장군님을 생각하며
죽어갔을 거고요
I'm equally sure they all died
thinking of you...
...every man jack of them, Jack.
모두들 말입니다
Supposing a bit of water
has gone off, eh?
물이 떨어졌을지도 모르죠
Certainly one can never be too sure
about those things.
그런 건
확실히 알기 힘들죠
절 보십시오
제가 더럽고 응고돼 보이나요?
But look at me.
Do I look all rancid and clotted?
Look at me, Jack. Look.
절 좀 보십시오!
전 물을 많이 마십니다
급수원이라 불릴 정도죠
And I drink a lot of water.
I'm what you might call a water man.
그렇지만 맹세코
And I can swear to you, my boy,
swear to you...
제 체액은
아무 이상 없습니다
...that there's nothing wrong
with my bodily fluids.
Not a thing, Jackie.
전혀요
자네 전쟁 포로가
돼본 적 있나?
Mandrake, were you ever
a prisoner of war?
Well, Jack, the time's running very--
시간이 없습니다...
- 뭐라고요?
- 전쟁포로가 돼본 적 있나?
- What?
- Were you ever a prisoner of war?
Yes, I was, as a matter of fact.
네, 있습니다
Did they torture you?
고문도 당했나?
그렇습니다
일본군이 그랬죠
Yes, they did.
I was tortured by the Japanese.
Not a pretty story.
유쾌한 얘긴 아닙니다
What happened?
어떻게 됐지?
글쎄요, 이런 상황에서
생각하긴 힘들군요
I don't know, Jack. It's difficult
to think under these conditions.
그러니까...
Well, what happened was...
...they got me on the old
Rangoon-Inchinawa Railway.
랑군의 오래된
기찻길로 끌고 가더니
I was laying train lines
for the bloody Japanese puff-puffs.
망할 놈의 일본 기관차가
오는 길에 눕히더군요
No, I mean, when they tortured you,
did you talk?
고문 받았을 때
자백을 했는지 궁금하네
아뇨...
No, l--
놈들은 제게 어떤 말도
기대하지 않았어요
Well, I don't think they wanted me
to talk, really, or say anything.
그저 재미삼아 그런 거죠
비열한 놈들
It was their way of having
a bit of fun, the swine.
The strange thing is,
they make such bloody good cameras.
그런 놈들이 카메라는
잘 만드는 게 의아합니다
Those clowns outside will give me
a good going-over soon for the code.
놈들이 곧 들이닥쳐
암호를 대라고 할 거야
맞는 말씀입니다
Yes, you may have quite a point
there, Jack.
고문을 잘 견딜 수 있을지
모르겠군
I don't know how well
I could stand up under torture.
고문을 잘 견디는 사람은
없습니다
The answer to that is,
no one ever does.
그러니까 제게 암호를
주십시오
And my advise to you
is to give me the code now.
If those devils come back
and try any rough stuff...
저런 사악한 집단이
또 쳐들어 오면
방금 전에 했던 것처럼
함께 싸우는 겁니다
...we'll fight them together
like we did just now on the floor.
장군님은 총을 드시고
전 총알을 조달하죠
You with your gun and me
with a belt of ammo, feeding you.
장군님 명령대로
잘 돕지 않았습니까?
"Feed me", you said,
and I was feeding you, Jack.
맨드레이크
You know, Mandrake...
...I happen to believe in
a life after this one...
내세가 있다고 믿게 됐네
...and I know I'll have to answer
for what I've done.
내가 한 일의 대가는
그때 받겠지
난 할 수 있어
And I think I can.
Yes, of course you can.
Of course you can. You can.
물론 하실 수 있습니다
전 독실한 신자랍니다
I'm a religious man myself,
you know.
I believe in all that sort of thing
and I'm hoping, you know, Jack--
저도 그런 걸 믿고
희망한답니다...
You've dropped your gun, Jack.
총을 떨어뜨리셨군요
No, Jack, let me take that for you.
제가 들어 드리죠
You know what I'm hoping? I'm hoping
you're going to give me the code, boy.
장군님이 암호를 알려
주신다면 더 바랄 게 없겠군요
You're going to wash and brush up?
What a good idea.
씻고 몸단장을 하신다고요?
좋은 생각입니다
씻고 나면 기분이
훨씬 좋아지죠
Always did wonders for a man,
a wash and brush up.
Water on the back of the neck
makes you feel marvellous.
목 뒤로 물을 끼얹으면
기분 죽입니다
바로 그거예요
시원한 샤워 후의 암호라!
That's what we need: water on
the back of the neck and the code.
Supposing I play a little guessing game
with you, Jack boy?
알아 맞추기 게임
형식인가요?
I'll try and guess
what the code is--
암호는 아마도...
Copilot to navigator.
I'm ready with the fuel figures now.
연료수치를
말씀 드리겠습니다
총 10만 9천 중...
We have 109,000 total...
주연료는 7만 9천이고
...79,000 in the mains...
보조 연료는 3만입니다
...and 30,000 in the auxiliaries.
And that works out
toroughly...
그 정도면 대략...
...seven hours, 15 minutes
endurance from this time.
7시간 15분간
버틸 수 있습니다
D.S.O. to Captain.
D.S.O.이다
I have an unidentified
radar blip.
미확인 물체 포착
Distance: 60 miles.
거리는 100킬로미터
속도 마하 3
Approximate speed:
Mach three.
Looks like
a missile tracking us.
미사일 공격 같다
Confirmed:
definite missile track.
미사일이 확실하다
Commence evasive action right.
방어태세 개시
미사일 접근 중
Missile still closing range.
Distance: 50 miles.
Continue evasive action.
거리 80킬로미터
계속 방어태세
Lock E.C.M. to target intercept mode.
표적 교란 모드 작동
E.C.M. locked to
target intercept mode.
표적 교란 모드 작동
미사일 계속 접근 진행 중
Missile still tracking
and closing distance.
Range: 40 miles.
Continue evasive action.
사정 거리 64킬로미터
계속 방어태세
Electronic Guidance Scrambler
to blue grid.
전자 주파수대 변환기 작동
미사일 계속 접근 중
Missile still tracking steady
and closing distance.
사정거리 48킬로미터
Range: 30 miles.
미사일 계속 접근 중
계속 방어태세
Missile still closing true and steady.
Continue evasive action.
Range: 20 miles.
사정거리 32킬로미터
Missile still closing distance
and tracking steady.
미사일 계속 접근 중
Attack range gate
on maximum scan.
공격 사정 거리 최대
Range gate on maximum scan.
Range: 10 miles.
사정거리 16킬로미터
미사일 추적 실패
방어태세 계속
Missile track deflecting.
Continue evasive action.
Deflection increasing.
Range: eight miles.
미사일 추적 실패
12킬로미터 접근
Deflection still increasing.
Range: six miles.
미사일 추적 실패
8킬로미터 접근
Missile still deflecting.
Range: four miles.
미사일 추적 실패
6킬로미터 접근
3킬로미터
미사일 추적 실패
Range: two miles.
Missile still deflecting.
1킬로미터
미사일 폭파됨
Range: one mile.
Missile detonated!
- Start lever to cut off!
- Cut off!
- 차단 레버 작동!
- 차단해
We're losin' power!
동력이 약해지고 있다
필수동력 재가동!
Re-select essential power!
필수동력 재가동 됨!
Essential power re-selected.
The hatch is stuck!
해치가 열리지 않습니다
비상 동력 가동!
Hit emergency power!
- 소화기 작동!
- 알았다
- Extinguishers!
- Roger!
- 스위치 전환!
- 전환함
- Transfer switches!
- Transferred!
- 펌프 작동 차단!
- 차단됨
- Boost pumps off!
- Cut off!
연료 밸브 3번, 4번, 6번!
Fuel valves three, four and six!
전속력!
Give me full power!
지구에 평화를
Peace on Earth.
P.O.E.
그래, P.O.E.
본질의 순수함
Purity of Essence.
O.P.O.E.
손 들어
Put your hands over your head.
What do you think you're doing?
Who are you?
무슨 짓이오?
누구지?
손을 들라니까
Put your hands over your head.
What kind of suit
do you call that, fella?
그 복장을 뭐라 부르나?
What do you mean, suit?
복장이라니?
이건 영국 공군복이고
This happens to be
an R.A.F. uniform...
...and I am Group Captain Lionel Mandrake,
General Ripper's executive officer.
난 리퍼 장군의 행정관
맨드레이크 공군 대령이네
Where's General Ripper?
리퍼 장군은 어딨소?
He's dead, in the bathroom.
화장실에 죽어 있지
Where's the bathroom?
화장실이 어디오?
당신 바로 옆이오
Next to you.
당신이 왜 이리
어리석게 구는지 모르겠지만
I don't know what stupid game
this is you're playing...
공격 명령 해제 암호를
알아냈으니
...but I've got a good idea
what the recall code is...
...and I have to get in touch
with SAC headquarters immediately!
즉시 본부에
연락해야 하오
손 들고
가만히 있으시오
Put your hands over your head
and keep 'em there! Go on.
Got any witnesses?
목격자는 있소?
목격자?
자살했다는데 무슨 소리요?
What are you talking about?
He shot himself!
While he was shavin'?
면도하다가 갑자기?
Now look, Colonel Bat Guano...
이봐요, 과노 대령
...if that really is your name...
진짜 이름인지 몰라도...
...may I tell you that I have
a very good idea--
알아낸 거 같소
I think, hope, pray--
what the recall code is.
해제 암호가 맞을 거요
장군이 늘 되뇌던
문구의 조합으로
It's some theme he kept repeating.
A variation on...
E.O.P.나
O.P.E.중 하나일 거요
..."Peace on Earth" or "Purity of Essence",
one of those.
손 머리에 얹고 나가시오
Put your hands on top of your head.
Start walkin'.
Don't you know that General Ripper
went mad...
리퍼 장군이 정신이 나가
소련 침공을 명령한 걸
모른단 말이오?
...and sent the whole Wing
to attack the Soviets?
- 무슨 말이오?
- 설명해 드리지
- What are you talkin' about?
- I'll tell you what I'm talking about.
이 긴급전화는
본부 직통이니까
I'm going to pick up this red telephone,
which is connected to SAC...
...and I hope--
내 생각에...
Blast. Blast.
제기랄
당신 부하 중 한 명이
전화선을 끊었나 보군
Shot away, I expect, by one of your men
during this ridiculous fighting!
좋소
Right.
당신에게 더 이상
낭비할 시간이 없소
All right, Charlie, I've been
wastin' too much time on you.
I got a lot of wounded men outside.
Start walkin'.
밖에 부상자들도 많은데
갑시다
C.R.M. 114를 포함한
모든 무전이 끊겼습니다
All the radio gear is out,
including the C.R.M. 114.
I think the auto-destruct mechanism
got hit and blew itself up.
자동 파괴 장치가
작동한 거 같습니다
The fire is out.
The emergency power is on.
소화 완료
비상 동력 가동
모든 계기 점검 완료
Everything checks out all right.
Will advise.
알았다
Roger. Navigator?
분당 연료 손실율 1-6-2로
I've worked out our rate of fuel loss
at approximately 1-6-2 per minute.
이에 따른 행동 반경상
This gives us a radius of action
sufficient to take out...
1번과 2번 목표물을
파괴할 수 있지만
...primary and secondary targets,
but we will not...
어떤 기지나 중립 국가로도
돌아갈 수 없습니다
...repeat, not be able to make it back
to any base or neutral country.
However, we would have
enough fuel to ditch...
하지만 좌표 0-0-3-6-9-1의
기상 관측선인
탱고 델타에
...at weather ship Tango Delta...
...grid coordinates 0-0-3-6-9-1.
불시착은 가능합니다
엔진이 3개 파손됐고
Well, boys,
we got three engines out.
기체엔 수없이 많은
총알 구멍이 났고
We got more holes in us
than a horse trader's mule.
무전기도 나가고
연료는 새는 데다
The radio is gone,
and we're leakin' fuel.
더 이상 낮게 날았다간
썰매 꼴이 되겠지만
And if we was flyin' any lower,
we'd need sleigh bells on this thing.
이로운 점도 있다
But we got one little budge
on them Ruskies.
이런 높이라면
위험하긴 하지만
At this height
they might harpoon us...
레이더 망엔 잡히지
않는다
...but they sure ain't gonna spot us
on no radar screen.
반대쪽으로
The other way.
- 어디로 데려가는 거요?
- 정문이오
- Where are you taking me?
- To the main gate.
Colonel, I must know what you think
has been going on here.
대령이 무슨 생각을 하는지
모르겠소
- You wanna know what I think?
- Yes.
- 내 생각을 듣고 싶소?
- 그렇소
내가 보기에 당신은
변절자 같소
I think you're some kind
of deviated "prevert".
리퍼 장군이 당신의
변절 행위를 알자
I think General Ripper found out
about your "preversion"...
변절성 반란을
일으켰던 거지
...and that you were organizing
some kind of mutiny of "preverts".
Now, move!
가시오!
소련이 침공 됐단 얘긴
금시초문이오
On top of that, I don't know anything
about any planes attacking Russia.
I was told to get Ripper on the phone
with the President of the United States.
내 임무는 리퍼 장군을
미 대통령과 통화하게 하는 거요
방금 대통령이라 했소?
Now just one second.
You just said "the president".
What about the president?
그렇소만?
The president wants to speak
to General Ripper, doesn't he?
대통령께서 리퍼 장군과
통화를 원하신다고요?
Now, General Ripper is dead,
is he not?
장군은 죽었습니다
그렇죠?
I am General Ripper's
executive officer...
난 장군의 부관이니
내가 대신 통화하는 게
당연하겠죠?
...so the president will want
to speak to me, won't he?
There's a telephone box over there
and the line may be open.
저기 공중전화가 있는데
통화가 가능할 거요
You wanna talk to
the President of the United States?
미국 대통령과
통화하고 싶소?
하고 싶은 게 아니라
해야만 하오
I don't want to talk to him, Colonel,
I've got to talk to him.
And if you don't put that gun away
and stop this stupid nonsense...
계속 총을 겨눈 채
어리석은 짓을 한다면
...the Court of Inquiry on this
will give you such a pranging...
나중에 사문위원회에서
처벌을 받아
화장실 청소원으로
전락하게 될 거요!
...you'll be lucky to end up wearing the
uniform of a bloody toilet attendant!
그럼 대통령과
통화해보시지
Go ahead, try and get the President
of the United States on the phone.
Try any "preversions",
I'll blow your head off.
허튼 짓 했다간
머리통을 날려버리겠소
교환? 맨드레이크 대령이오
Operator? This is
Group Captain Lionel Mandrake.
버펠슨 공군기지에서
전화하는 거요
I'm speaking from
Burpelson Air Force Base.
긴급한 상황이니
워싱턴 DC의 국방성에 있는
Something urgent has come up and I want
you to place a person-to-person call...
머킨 머플리 대통령과
연결해 주시오
...with President Merkin Muffley
in the Pentagon, Washington, D.C.
버펠슨 3-9-1-8-0이오
Burpelson 3-9-1-8-0.
농담 아니오
미합중국 대통령 말이오
No, I'm perfectly serious.
The President of the United States.
이런
동전이 모자라는군
I'm sorry,
I haven't got enough change.
Could you make this
a collect call, Operator?
수신자 부담으로
해줄 순 없겠소?
잠시만요, 교환
받지 않겠다고 하는군
Just one second, Operator.
They won't accept the call.
55센트 있소?
Have you got 55 cents?
전쟁터에 동전 가지고
다니는 거 봤소?
Do you think I'd go into combat
with loose change in my pocket?
이봐요
Operator, look.
보통 장거리 전화로는
안되겠소?
Is it possible to make this
an ordinary trunk call?
그걸 뭐라더라...
Well, what do you call it?
You know--
Oh, station-to-station.
번호로 하는 통화 말이오
젠장, 아직
20센트 모자라는군
Oh, blast!
I'm still 20 cents short.
잠깐 기다려 주시겠소?
Operator, hold on.
I shan't keep you a second.
대령, 코카콜라 판매기를
쏴서 열어요
Colonel, that Coca-Cola machine.
I want you to shoot the lock off it.
안에 동전이 있을 테니까
There may be change in there.
사유 재산이잖소
That's private property.
Can you possibly imagine
what is going to happen to you...
당신이 대통령과의
통화를 방해했다는 사실을
그들이 알게 된다면
당신 신상에는
...your frame outlook,
way of life and everything...
상상하기 힘든 일이
일어날 거요
...when they learn you have obstructed
a phone call to the president?
알겠소?
어서 쏘시오!
Can you imagine?
Shoot it off!
Shoot with the gun! That's what
the bullets are for, you twit!
총은 그런데 쓰는 거요
멍청하긴!
좋소, 원하는 대로 하겠지만
Okay, I'm gonna get
your money for you.
But if you don't get the president on
the phone, you know what's gonna happen?
만약 대통령과 통화 못 하면
어떻게 될지 아오?
You're gonna have to answer
to the Coca-Cola Company.
콜라회사에 해명을
해야 할 거요
SAC 통신 통제실이다
This is SAC
Communications Control.
843 폭격대대에 의해
The recall code O.P.E...
공격 명령 해제 암호인
...is being acknowledged "roger"...
O.P.E. 확인됨
...by elements of
the 8-4-3 Bomb Wing.
자세한 내용은 다음과 같다
These are the details.
작전 12, 22, 30, 38은
Missions 12, 22, 30 and 38...
적에 의해 파괴됐고
...are reported destroyed
by enemy action.
All other missions have
acknowledged recall code.
타 작전은 모두 취소됐다
This is SAC Communications Control.
SAC 통신실에서 전함
Over and out.
이상
여러분
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Gentlemen.
대통령 각하
Mr. President.
전 감상적인 사람은 아니지만
I'm not a sentimentalist by nature...
...but I think I know what's
in every heart in this room.
다들 기분이 어떤지
짐작이 됩니다
I think we all ought
to bow our heads...
우리 모두 머리를 숙이고
우리의 결정에 대해
감사기도를 드립시다
...and give a prayer of thanks
for our deliverance.
주여
Lord...
두려움의 계곡에서 온
죽음의 천사가
...we have heard the wings
of the Angel of Death...
우리 머리 위에서
날개짓을 할 때
...fluttering over our heads
from the Valley of Fear.
You have seen fit to deliver us
from the forces of evil--
악의 힘을 빌리는 걸
보셨습니다...
Excuse me, sir.
각하
Premier Kissoff's calling again
and he's hopping mad.
서기장이 화가 나서
전화하셨습니다
활동 중인 엔진에서
연료가 계속 샙니다
Fuel flow on active engines
and leakage has increased.
분당 소비량 2-0-5
Now works out at 2-0-5.
Estimate remaining fuel...
남은 연료는...
8-7-9-0
...at 8-7-9-0.
알았다
분당 205...
Roger.
Confirm 2-0-5 per minute...
남은 연료 8790 확인
...and remaining fuel 8-7-9-0.
No, no, Dimitri,
there must be some mistake.
아니오
착오가 있었을 겁니다
No, I'm certain of that.
아니, 확신하오
의심의 여지가 없다니까요
I'm perfectly certain
of that, Dimitri.
잠시 기다려 주시오
뭐라 그러는지 아오?
Just a second.
You know what he says?
폭격기 한 대가
귀환하지 않았다는군
He says one of the planes
hasn't turned back.
우리측 공군 참모한테서
얻은 정보로
He says according to information
forwarded by our Air Staffs...
폭격기가 라퓨터 미사일 기지로
향하고 있다는군
...it's headed for
the missile complex at Laputa.
말도 안됩니다
That's impossible, Mr. President.
상황판을 보십시오
I mean,
look at the big board.
34대 폭격기 중
30대가 귀환했고
Thirty-four planes, 30 recalls
acknowledged and four splashes...
격추된 4대중 한 대가
라퓨터 행이었죠
...and one of them
was targeted for Laputa.
Dimitri, look, we've got
an acknowledgement from every plane...
당신이 격추시킨
격추기 4대를 제외하면
모든 폭격기에서
연락을 받았소
...except the four you've shot down.
잠시 기다려주시오
Hang on a second, Dimitri.
서기장 말로는
3대만 격추됐고
He says their air defense now only
claims three aircraft confirmed.
한 대는
파손만 된 것 같다는군
The fourth may only be damaged.
각하
Mr. President...
공산주의자들의
수작이 분명합니다
...I'm beginnin' to smell
a big, fat Commie rat.
우릴 침공하기 위한 구실로
I mean, supposin' Kissoff is lyin'
about that fourth plane...
...just lookin' for
an excuse to clobber us?
네 번째 폭격기에 대해
거짓말을 하는 게 아닐까요?
그렇다면 보통 문제가
아닙니다
If the spaghetti hits the fan,
we're in trouble.
Dimitri, look,
if this report is true...
만약 당신 말대로
...and the plane manages
to bomb the target...
우리측 폭격기가
목표물을 폭파하면
심판의 기계가
작동하는 거요?
...is this gonna set off
the doomsday machine?
정말이오?
Are you sure?
그렇다면 그 폭격기를
격추시킬 생각이군요?
Well, I guess you're just gonna have
to get that plane, Dimitri.
대원들이 레이더 망을
방해한 건 안됐지만
I'm sorry they're jamming
your radar and flying so low...
그렇게 훈련 받았으니
당연하오
...but they're trained to do it.
선제공격이죠
It's initiative.
Look, Dimitri, you know
exactly where they're going...
당신은 그들의 목적지를
잘 아니까
폭격기 한 대 정도는
막을수 있겠지
...and I'm sure your entire air defense
can stop a single plane.
심판의 기계가 작동하면
피차간에 좋을 게 없소
It's not gonna help either one of us
if the doomsday machine goes off, is it?
이런 때 이성을 잃어서
좋을 건 없소
There's no point in you getting
hysterical at a moment like this!
말할 때는 신중하시오
Keep your feet on the ground
when you're talking, Dimitri.
I am not--
I am not getting--
그런 게 아니라...
No, Dimitri, I'm just worried.
그저 걱정돼서 그렇소
그뿐이오
That's all.
Now look, if our Air Staffs say
its primary target is Laputa...
목표물이 각각 라퓨터와
보르초프라는 얘기가
우리측 공군에서 나왔다면
맞을 거요
...and its secondary target is Borchov,
it's true.
믿어야 합니다
You gotta believe it!
딱 한마디만...
Dimitri, can I give you
just one word--
조언 한마디 해도 되겠소?
Can I give you just one word
of advice, Dimitri?
잘 들어요
Listen, Dimitri.
그 두 지역에 모든 전력을
투입하면 될 거요
Put everything you've got into
those two sectors, and you can't miss!
이 속도로 계속 연료를 잃으면
Sir, if we continue to lose fuel
at the present rate...
비행 가능 시간이
38분이 되어
...I estimate we only have
38 minutes flying time...
제1 목표지역에도
도달할 수 없습니다
...which will not even take us
as far as the primary.
Doggone it, Sweets, you told me that
you could get me to the primary!
제1 목표지역은
문제없다고 했잖나!
죄송합니다, 그 당시에는
누출량이...
I'm sorry, sir. That estimate was based
on the original loss rate factor...
이 정도는 아니었죠
...not at 2-0-5.
수단과 방법을 가리지 말고
I don't give a hoot in hell
how you do it...
제1 목표지역에는
도착하게나
...you just get me to
the primary, you hear?
I'm sorry, sir,
but those are the figures.
죄송합니다만
예측대로입니다
기상 관측선까지
겨우 가겠군요
We'll be lucky to reach
weather ship at Tango Delta.
제기랄!
Well, shoot!
We ain't come this far just
to dump this thing in the drink.
바다에 빠지려고 이렇게
멀리까지 온 줄 아나?
가장 가까운 목적지는
어디인가?
What's the nearest
target of opportunity?
유출이 늘지만 않는다면
Sir, if the rate of loss
does not increase...
003691 좌표의
...we have a chance
to reach target 3-8-4...
...grid coordinate 0-0-3-6-9-1 ...
384목표물을 폭파하고
기상 관측선으로
갈 수 있을 겁니다
...and possibly make it from there
to the Tango Delta weather ship.
목표물은 무엇인가?
What kind of a target
is that, anyhow?
Sir, that's the I.C.B.M.
complex at Kotloss.
코틀로스의
I.C.B.M. 기지입니다
All right.
Designating new target: 3-8-4.
그렇다면 표적 384를
새롭게 지정한다
Give me a headin' on that just as soon
as you get it worked out.
즉시 비행 항로를 정하라
행운을 빌 수 밖에요
우린 한 배를 탔습니다
We'll keep our fingers crossed.
Remember, we're all in this together.
당신 뒤엔 항상 우리가
지키고 있소
We're right behind you,
we're with you all the way.
이 전화선은 열어놓겠소
Yes. We'll keep the line open.
알았소
All right, Dimitri.
General Turgidson...
장군
폭격기가 무사할
가능성이 있소?
...is there really a chance
for that plane to get through?
Mr. President,
if I may speak freely.
솔직히 말씀 드리자면
소련인들은 허풍은 심하지만
노하우가 부족합니다
The Ruskie talks big, but frankly
we think he's short of know-how.
무지한 사람들로
아군만큼 기계를 잘 알지 못하죠
You can't expect ignorant peons
to understand a machine like our boys.
모욕하려는 게 아니오, 대사
That's not meant as an insult,
Mr. Ambassador.
We all know how much guts
the average Ruskie's got.
사회주의자들이 배짱
두둑하다는 건 잘 압니다
Look at all of them Nazis killed
off, and they still wouldn't quit!
나치가 절멸시킨 사람들을
보세요, 끊임 없습니다
요점이 대체 뭐요?
Can't you stick to the point?
실력 있는 조종사에겐
Well, sir,
if the pilot's good, see--
저공 비행은 식은죽
먹기입니다
...I mean, if he's really sharp,
he can barrel that baby in so low.
정말 볼만하죠!
B52 같은 전투기가 날 땐
You oughta see it! It's a sight!
A big plane like a 52! Vroom!
농가 앞마당의 닭들까지
심하게 놀라기도 하죠!
Its jet exhaust fryin' chickens
in the barnyard!
- 빠져나갈 가능성은 있소?
- 가능성요?
- But has he got a chance?
- Has he got a chance?
그럼요...
Hell, ye--
기장님
Navigator to Captain.
표적까지 1.6킬로미터
남았습니다
Approaching target
at distance 1-0 miles.
표적 제거 준비
Switch from green grid
to target orange.
알았다
마지막으로 폭탄 점검
Roger.
Ready for final bomb run check.
- 공격하라
- 알겠습니다
- Take over, Ace.
- Roger.
- D.S.O. 준비 완료
- 폭격수 준비 완료
- D.S.O. ready.
- Bombardier ready, sir.
폭탄 퓨즈, 안전장치 작동
Bomb fusing, master safety on.
전기 기압 장치 작동
Electronic, barometric,
time and impact.
폭탄 퓨즈, 안전장치 작동
Bomb fusing,
master safeties on.
전기 기압 장치 작동
Electronic, barometric,
time and impact.
지상 충돌 퓨즈
지연 상태 황색 3번
Fuse for ground burst.
Delay factor yellow three.
지상 충돌 퓨즈
지연 상태 황색 3번
Fuse for ground burst.
Delay factor yellow three.
폭탄 퓨즈 회로
점검 완료
Bomb fusing circuits
one through four, test.
폭탄 퓨즈 회로
점검 완료, 개시
Bomb fusing circuits one through four,
test. Lights on.
폭탄 무장 점검 완료
Bomb arming test lights on,
one through four.
폭탄 무장 점검 완료
Bomb arming test lights on,
one through four.
제1 폭파 스위치 수동 작동
Engage primary trigger switch override.
Primary trigger switch override engaged.
Track indicators
to maximum deflection.
추적범위 최대
Track indicators
to maximum deflection.
추적범위 최대화
뇌관 작동
Detonator set to zero altitude.
제1 안전장치 제거
Release first safety.
First safety released.
제1 안전장치 제거됨
- 제1 안전장치
- 제2 안전장치 제거
- First safety.
- Release second safety.
Second safety released.
제2 안전장치 제거됨
Second safety.
제2 안전장치
폭탄 투하구 회로
점검 완료
Check bomb door circuits
one through four.
폭탄 투하구 닫힘
폭탄 투하구 회로...
Uh, bomb door circuits...
적색 경보
...negative function, lights red.
-Switch in backup circuits.
- Roger.
- 보조 회로 전환
- 알았습니다
Backup circuits switched in.
Still negative function.
여전히 반응 없습니다
비상 회로 작동
Engage emergency power.
Roger.
알겠습니다
비상 회로도
반응 없습니다
Emergency power on.
Still negative function.
수동 작동으로 전환!
Operate manual override!
Roger.Still negative function.
알겠습니다
반응 없습니다
케이블이 파손된 것
같습니다
The Teleflex drive cable
must be sheared away.
- 폭발성 볼트 발사!
- 알겠습니다
- Fire the explosive bolts!
- Roger.
발사 스위치
반응 없습니다
회로가 손상됐습니다
Still negative, sir.
The operating circuits are dead, sir.
대기하고 있게
직접 내려가 볼 테니
Stay on the bomb run, Ace. I'm goin'
down below and see what I can do.
그대로 있게나
Stay on the bomb run.
기필코 그 놈 의 문을
열고 말겠다
I'm gonna get them doors open
if it harelips everybody on Bear Creek!
안녕, 존
표적 거리 점검
Target orange grid reference checks.
표적 거리 12킬로미터
Target distance: eight miles.
알았다, 12 킬로미터
Roger. Eight miles.
황색 모드 원격 유도
컴퓨터 작동
Telemetric guidance computer
into orange grid.
황색 모드 원격유도
컴퓨터 작동
Telemetric guidance computer
into orange grid.
표적까지 11킬로미터
Target distance: seven miles.
항로수정 -7
Correct track indicator:
minus seven.
알았다
G.P.I. 가속 점검하라
Roger. Seven miles.
Check G.P.I. acceleration factor.
G.P.I. 가속 점검 완료
G.P.I. acceleration factor set.
표적 거리 9킬로미터
Target distance: six miles.
알겠다
자동무선 레이더 작동
Roger. Six miles.
Pulse ident transponder active.
자동무선 레이더 작동
표적 거리 8킬로미터
Target distance: five miles.
8킬로미터
폭발 적중 모드
Five miles. Homing alignment
factor to zero mode.
폭발 적중 모드 작동
Homing alignment factor
to zero mode.
표적 거리 6킬로미터
Target distance: four miles.
알았다, 6킬로미터
Roger. Four miles.
수동 텔레플렉스에
자동 C.D.C. 연결
Auto C.D.C. into
manual Teleflex link.
수동 텔레플렉스에
자동 C.D.C.연결
Auto C.D.C. into
manual Teleflex link.
표적 거리 4킬로미터
Target distance: three miles.
알았다, 4킬로미터
Roger. Three miles.
표적 육안 확인!
소령님은 어디 계시지?
Target in sight!
Where in hell is Major Kong?
소령님 어디 계셔?
What about Major Kong?
인류의 세포핵 보존도
Mr. President, I would not
rule out the chance...
물론 고려해야죠
...to preserve a nucleus
of human specimens.
It would be quite easy...
깊은 지하에선
꽤 쉬운 일입니다
...at the bottom of some
of our deeper mine shafts.
수천 피트 깊이의 지하를
방사능이 뚫을 순 없죠
The radioactivity would never penetrate
a mine some thousands of feet deep.
몇 주면 사람이 살 만한
넓은 공간을
And in a matter of weeks, sufficient
improvements in dwelling space...
충분히 만들수 있습니다
...could easily be provided.
지하에 얼마나
있어야 하오?
How long would you have
to stay down there?
그러니까...
Well, that's, you know--
Cobalt thorium G.
코발트 토륨 G의...
방사능 반감기를 고려하면...
Radioactive half-life of--
한 1백년 정도 될 겁니다
I would think that possibly
one hundred years.
사람들이 지하에서
1백 년을 지낼 수 있소?
You mean, people could actually
stay down there for 100 years?
어렵지는 않습니다
메인 총통
It would not be difficult,
Mein Fuhrer.
원자로는...
Nuclear reactors could--
죄송합니다, 각하
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
Nuclear reactors could provide
power almost indefinitely.
원자로는 거의 무제한적인
위력을 공급할 겁니다
온실에서 식물을 키우고
Greenhouses could maintain
plant life.
가축을 길러
잡아 먹을수 있습니다
Animals could be bred
and slaughtered.
쓸만한 지하갱도를
찾는 것이 급선무입니다
A quick survey would have to be made of
the available mine sites in the country.
수십만의 인간이 살 만한
But I would guess
that a dwelling space...
...for several hundred thousand of
our people could easily be provided.
지하 대피소는
쉽게 확보할 수 있습니다
Well, I would hate
to have to decide...
대피할 사람을
결정하는 게
곤란하겠군
...who stays up and who goes down.
그 또한
별문제 없습니다
Well, that would not be
necessary, Mr. President.
컴퓨터만 있으면
간단하죠
It could easily be accomplished
with a computer.
컴퓨터에 적당한
조건이 입력됩니다
And the computer could
be set and programmed...
젊음, 건강...
...to accept factors
from youth, health...
번식력, 지성...
...sexual fertility, intelligence...
필수 기술 등이죠
...and a cross-section
of necessary skills.
Of course, it would be
absolutely vital...
물론 주요 정부인사와
군수뇌부 인사는
당연히 포함됩니다
...that our top government
and military men be included...
통솔력과 전통을
지켜나가기 위해서죠
...to foster and impart the required
principles of leadership and tradition.
엄청난 속도로
번식할 겁니다
Naturally, they would breed
prodigiously.
시간은 많고
할 일은 없으니까요
There would be much time
and little to do.
적당한 번식기술과
남자 당 여자의 수가
But with the proper breeding techniques
and a ratio of, say...
10명 정도라면
...ten females to each male...
20년 안에 현재의
국민총생산 수준에
...they could then work their way back
to the present gross national product...
이를 겁니다
...within 20 years.
But look, Doctor.
Wouldn't this nucleus of survivors...
하지만 박사
혹시 생존자들 중
슬픔과 고뇌에 사로잡혀
...be so grief-stricken
and anguished that they...
죽은 자들을 부러워하는
사람은 없겠소?
...well, envy the dead
and not want to go on living?
그렇지 않습니다
No, sir. Excuse me.
지하세계에 내려가도
모두 살아남을 겁니다
When they go down into the mine,
everyone would still be alive.
충격적인 기억 대신
There would be
no shocking memories...
함께 오지 못한 사람들에
대한 향수와
...and the prevailing emotion will be one
of nostalgia for those left behind...
앞으로 펼쳐질
...combined with a spirit of...
모험에 대한 호기심이
만연할 겁니다!
...bold curiosity for
the adventure ahead!
박사님은...
Doctor...
1대 10의 남녀비율에 대해
언급하셨는데
...you mentioned the ratio
of ten women to each man.
그렇다면 소위 말하는
일부일처제의
Now, wouldn't that
necessitate the abandonment...
남녀 관계는
파괴되는 거군요
...of the so-called
monogamous sexual relationship?
남자 입장에서는 말입니다
I mean, as far as men were concerned?
유감스럽게도 그렇습니다
Regrettably, yes.
하지만 인류의 미래를 위해
감수해야 합니다
But it is a sacrifice required
for the future of the human race.
우선 드리고 싶은 말은
남성들은 중요한 일을
I hasten to add that since each man
will be required to do prodigious...
맡게 될 테니
...service along these lines...
여성의 선택 조건 중
성적인 특질이
...the women will have to be selected
for their sexual characteristics...
가장 중요한 요소가
될 겁니다
...which will have to be of
a highly stimulating nature.
대단히 훌륭한 견해라고
생각하오, 박사
I must confess, you have an
astonishingly good idea there, Doctor.
고맙습니다
Thank you, sir.
We ought to look at this
from the military point of view.
군사적 입장에서
생각해야 합니다
만약 소련 놈들만
I mean,
supposing the Ruskies...
커다란 폭탄을
숨겨 놨다면
...stashed away some big bombs,
see, and we didn't?
1백 년 후
우린 전멸이라고요!
When they come out in 100 years,
they could take over!
I agree, Mr. President.
옳습니다, 각하
기습 공격으로 지하 기지를
점령할지도 모르죠
They might try a sneak attack so they
could take over our mine shaft space.
이번 일로 소련이
영토 확장정책을
It'd be extremely naive of us to
imagine that these new developments...
바꿀지도 모른다는 생각은
너무 순진한 겁니다!
...are gonna cause any change
in Soviet expansionist policy!
항상 경계를 강화해야 합니다!
I mean, we must be
increasingly on the alert...
놈들이 다른 지하 기지를
습격해서
...to prevent them from taking over
other mine shaft space...
엄청난 번식으로
수적 우위를 차지하면
...in order to breed more
prodigiously than we do...
지상에 나갔을 때
낭패를 볼 겁니다!
...thus knocking us out through
superior numbers when we emerge!
각하, 분리 대피소는
절대 안됩니다!
Mr. President, we must not allow
a mine-shaft gap!
각하!
Sir!
계획이 있습니다...
I have a plan--
메인 총통...
Mein Fuhrer...
내가 걷다니!
I can walk!